MIKE TSOU

(626) 278-6737 **♀** San Francisco Bay Area in miketsou mikeytsou

SUMMARY

I'm a Software Engineer with an emphasis on Front End Development. I have a Communications degree and three years experience with data collection and analysis relating to market research strategies. My passion for programming stems from my love for all things tech. My primary focus is to build web applications with the latest technologies and work with a company that will enable me to grow and develop my skills.

SKILLS

PROFICIENT: JavaScript, RubyOnRails, Express, React, Redux, Jquery, Ajax, MongoDB, HTML5, CSS3, RSpec, Jasmine, Sass, Bootstrap, SemanticUI, MVC, PostgreSQL, Git, Heroku, Node, Agile, Lodash

EXPOSURE: ReactNative, Materialize, Xcode, Angular, Python

PROJECTS

TODOAPI (CLICK TO VIEW) Nov 2017 - Nov 2017

Created a JSON REST API with Express and MongoDB and then built a simple todo list single-page application using the API.

Tech Stack: Node, Express, MongoDB, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Jquery

PORTFOLIO Oct 2017 - Oct 2017

My personal website detailing my background, skills, projects, and my contact information.

Tech Stack: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Jquery

EFEEDBACK Aug 2017 - Sep 2017

A MERN stack application that allows users to send out bulk email surveys to collect some amount of feedback from their customers.

Tech Stack: Node, Express, Passport, MongoDB, Mongoose, StripeAPI, SendGridAPI, React, Redux, ReactRouter, HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript

Jun 2017 - Jun 2017 **DAILY HABITS**

A journaling application that allows users to keep track of their daily activities and see their weekly progress/statistics via web browser or texting with a mobile device.

Tech Stack: RubyOnRails, ReactNative, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TwilioAPI, GoogleMapsAPI, WeatherUndergroundAPI, and PostgreSQL

Jun 2017 - Jun 2017 CRABALICIOUS FILMS

A web application that allows users to rate and review films, comment on other users reviews, and sort by categories.

Tech Stack: RubyOnRails, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, and JavaScript

EMPLOYMENT

NETPOP **Project Manager**

San Francisco Apr 2013 - Aug 2016

Los Angeles

- Managing and contributing to the daily execution processes of design, programming, quality control, data collecting/processing, analysis, and
- Oversee employees, translators, and 3rd party vendors for qualitative and quantitative market research studies relating to user experience, customer satisfaction, and product development.
- Successful launch of projects by meeting deadlines, hitting targeted guotas, and developing team dynamics.

FARMERS INSURANCE

Sep 2008 - Dec 2009

Insurance Agent

• Selling life, property and casualty, health, automotive, and other types of insurance policies.

- Perform administrative tasks such as maintaining records and handling policy renewals.
- Calculate premiums and establish payment methods.
- Averaged three clients a week making cold calls and generating leads.

ORINDA COUNTRY CLUB Customer Service

Orinda Apr 2007 - May 2008

- Provide service for all club members needing assistance.
- Running errands around the area for the pro shop.
- Clean and store members property for their next arrival.
- Set up and run tournaments.

EDUCATION

San Francisco State University

Bachelor of Arts Communications 2012

Dev Bootcamp

18 week immersive web development bootcamp